Olena Sinotova

**Kremenchuk,Ukraine (remotely)

Telegram LinkedIn Skype



I am a junior QA Engineer open to challenging and interesting work in an exciting environment and with a desire to succeed professionally in QA. I have an analytical mindset, proactive thinking, good theoretical knowledge and communication skills.

SUMMARY

Experience in testing of web and mobile applications

Experience in creating of Test documentation: test cases, checklists and bug reports

Experience with systems: JIRA, Trello

Basic experience with JavaScript, GIT, SQL, traffic tools, API testing

Understanding of client-server architecture (HTTP(s), REST, SOAP)

Understanding of Agile frameworks (Scrum, Kanban)

Knowledge of SDLC, STLC, BLC

Knowledge of HTML, CSS

Knowledge of the QA principles and approaches

Knowledge of the types, levels of testing and testdesign techniques

Tools: Chrome DevTools, Charles, Fiddler, Postman, SQLite

WORK EXPERIENCE

Internship, MasterDynamix, Kyiv November 2022 — November 2022

Internship on a real project. Interaction with the team through Jira. Functional and UX/UI testing of the Report menu. Created a checklist for testing and test cases. Wrote bug reports in Jira.

Apprenticeship, QWASAR Silicon Valley November 2022 – December 2022

Introduction to fullstack development. Completed 15 projects in addition to coding exercises at Silicon Valley standards covering fundamental concepts of fullstack engineering in Javascript programming.

Gained practical experience in coding using HTML, CSS, Javascript. Learned to work with the terminal and GIT.

Chief accountant, online store "rezina.cc", Kharkiv September 2015 – May 2022

Communication with the IT department regarding the development of new features for accountants. Experience with CRM systems.

When my department needed work automation, I provided my ideas to the IT department where some functionality should be added and what this functionality should do. The IT department coded and handed over their developments to me for testing. When I found bugs, I contacted the IT department to fix them.

EDUCATION

QA Engineer Manual, TechMission, Kyiv October 2022 — December 2022

Accounting and audit, Kharkiv National Economic University
September 2009 — February 2015

LANGUAGES

English - Intermediate

Ukrainian - Native